Smell that?
闻到没?
That's the smell of new comic books.
新漫画书的味道
They're on me today, boys.
哥们 今儿个都算我账上
You're paying?
你付钱?
Have you been selling
your sperm again?
你又卖精子了?
No, I'm celebrating.
不 庆祝下
As we speak,
the space shuttle is docking
我们说话这当儿
at the International Space Station
航天飞机正
对接国际空间站
where it will deploy the Wolowitz
Zero-Gravity Waste Disposal System.
其采用了Wolowitz零重力废物处理系统
Get over yourself.
It's a high-tech toilet.
少臭美了 不过是高科技厕所
Just think. Thanks to your hard work,
an international crew of astronauts
想想吧 多亏了你的付出
一飞船的国际宇航员
will "boldly go
where no man has gone before."
都能"大胆去往无人探索的地方"
- Is that supposed to be funny?
- I believe it is.
- 你这是搞笑咩?
- 我想是的
The combination of
the Star Trek reference
引用星际迷航的话来玩
and the play on words involving
the double-meaning of the verb "to go"
"去"和"冲"的文字游戏
suggests that Leonard is mocking
your efforts in space plumbing.
表示Leonard在幽默的嘲笑你
对宇航管道装置下的良苦用心
Okay, make your little jokes,
好啦 笑你们的吧
but of the four of us,
I'm the only one making
但四个人中 只有我对科技
any real-world contribution
to science and technology.
做出了实际贡献
He's right. This is an important
achievement, for two reasons.
他说的对 基于两点原因
这是一项重大的成果
Number one...
第一...
and, of course, number two!
还有 当然了 第二!
Clever!
行啊你!
Playing on the use
of cardinal numbers
用基数词做文章
as euphemisms for bodily functions.
来委婉表达人体机能
Here, Sheldon,
I pulled the new Hellboy for you.
来 Sheldon 给你新的地狱男孩
It's mind-blowing.
绝对大跌眼镜
Excuse me.
你咋回事啊
Spoiler alert.
剧透啦
I didn't spoil anything.
我啥也没透啊
You told me it's mind-blowing.
你都说会大跌眼镜了
So, my mind is going into it
pre-blown.
所以我看之前 眼镜就提前跌了
And once a mind is pre-blown,
it cannot be re-blown.
提前跌完 就不能够再跌了
I'm sorry.
对不起了
Said the Grinch to Christmas.
扫兴鬼对圣诞节如是说
(苏斯博士书中 搅乱圣诞节的角色)
- Can I talk to you about something?
- What's up?
- 嘿 Leonard 咱谈谈成吗?
- 行啊 啥事?
Remember I went out with Penny,
a couple weeks ago?
记得几周前我和你朋友Penny约会不?
- Yeah, vaguely.
- Sure you remember.
- 嗯 记不太清了
- 才怪嘞
You went to the bar
and made a fool of yourself
那晚你去酒吧自欺欺人
trying to pick up strange women.
打算把陌生美眉
What about it?
咋了呢?
The thing is,
the date didn't go that well.
是这样 约会不太成功
Too bad.
真遗憾
I guess the thing to do now
is just pick yourself up,
我想现在你该站起来
dust yourself off,
forget it and move on.
振作一下 忘记此事 向前看
- I can't do that.
- Why the hell not?
- 不行的
- 有啥不行的吧?
'Cause we're going out
again tomorrow.
因为明晚我们又要约会了
Excuse me, Stuart.
打扰下 Stuart
Have you read the new Flash?
- 看了最新的闪电侠没?
- 没有
Well, I have
and it will knock your socks off!
我看完了 这期会赞得你下巴都掉下来的
Good luck getting them back on.
祝你能把它推回去
This is probably my last shot with Penny
and I don't want to screw it up.
总之 这是我和Penny的最后机会了
我不想搞砸了
Nobody wants that.
谁想搞砸啊
So, here's my question:
It's the second date,
所以我的问题就来了 第二次约会
you think she'll be expecting things
你觉得她会不会想来点...
to get physical?
身体接触?
Gee...
哎呀...
My initial reaction is "no,"
我第一反应是"不想"
but let me think about it
and get back to you.
但还是让我想想吧 回来告诉你
So, you'll give me a call?
那你打给我?
- Yeah, or you call me.
- Great.
- 嗯 你打给我也成
- 好
Or nobody calls anyone.
谁也不给谁打更成
Interesting.
有点意思
Penny's current suitor asking advice
from her former suitor.
Penny的现追求者向前追求者取经
You know, thanks
for closed-captioning my pain, Raj.
谢谢你解说我的痛楚 Raj
Hey, wanna make sure
he gets nowhere with Penny
嘿 想既不让他和Penny有进展
又不妨碍你和他俩的友情吗
without jeopardizing your friendship
with either of them?
洗耳恭听
I'm listening.
让他做过去两年来你和她做的事
Just tell him to do everything
you've done with her
荣誉出品
for the last two years.
翻译: penny  Dr.Agon 王
校对: penny
Subtitles: The FW Team
- How's it going?
- Good, good. You?
- 嘿 Leonard
- 哦 嗨
Fine.
- 怎么样?
- 蛮好 蛮好 你呢?
Can I ask you something?
挺好的
Sure.
问你点事好不?
You know your friend Stuart?
好呀
He asked me out again
and I said yes,
- 记得你朋友Stuart哈?
- 嗯
and then I started thinking
maybe I should talk to you first.
他又约我出去 我答应了
About what?
然后寻思着 我似乎应该现跟你谈谈
Does it bother you,
me going out with one of your friends?
谈啥?
'Cause you know, you and me...
你会介意不 我跟你朋友约会?
No, that's the past.
因为那啥嘛 你和我...
I'm really more
of a "right now" kind of guy.
不会啦 那都老黄历了
You know, living in the moment.
我可是那种更计较现在的人
Although I do have to live a little
in the future, 'cause that's my job.
懂吧 活在当下
Of course, my fondness
for classic science fiction
虽说我的确需要关注未来
因为我的工作嘛
does draw my attention backwards,
当然啦 我对经典科幻小说的喜爱
会把我的焦点拉回一点点
but those stories often
take place in the future.
但那些故事常常发生在未来嘛
In conclusion, no,
it doesn't bother me.
总之了 我不介意
Okay, well,
that's really cool of you.
好 你能这样想真好
I wouldn't say cool.
I'd just say... "That's Leonard!"
不是啥好不好的
要我说是"Leonard就是这种人嘛!"
In that case,
do you mind giving me some advice?
既然酱紫 那你能给点啥建议不?
About Stuart?
Stuart的?
Love to.
原意啊
He's very shy.
他很害羞
How do I make him feel
more comfortable around me?
怎么能让他在我身边自在点?
First of all, don't underestimate
the value of discomfort.
首先 不要低估不自在的价值
Really?
真的呀?
Stuart thrives under pressure.
Stuart在压力下爆发
That's why he works in
a comic book store.
所以他在漫画书店工作嘛
It's Stuart.
是Stuart
You're not going to answer it?
你不打算接?
He wants to talk about Penny.
I don't want to talk about Penny.
他想谈Penny的事 我不想谈Penny
You're making an assumption.
你的假设而已啊
Perhaps the comic book store
is on fire.
或许是漫画书店着火了呢
And he needs your assistance.
他需要你的帮助
Why would he call me?
那打给我干啥?
We don't know.
不知道呀
And if you don't answer the phone,
we can't know.
你要是不接电话呢 我们也知道不了
I'm not answering the phone.
我才不要接电话
Answer the phone, Leonard.
接电话 Leonard
There, it went to voice mail.
好啦 转接语音信箱啦
Aren't you going to check
your messages?
你不读你的信息吗?
You have to check your messages!
不要
The living of a message
is one half of a social contract
你必须读下信息 Leonard!
which is completed by the
checking of the message.
既然留信息那就要读信息
才能实现这一社会契约
If that contract breaks down,
如果这契约破碎了
then all social contracts break down
and we descend into anarchy.
那所有社会契约都会破碎
我们会陷入混乱状态
It must be hell inside your head.
你脑子里一定纠结死了吧
At times.
偶尔
Guys, we have a code red.
伙计们 我们有紧急情况了
"Code Red" the hospital emergency alert,
the computer worm,
紧急情况是指医院紧急警报?
电脑病毒?
or the cherry-flavored soft drink
from the makers of Mountain Dew?
还是Mountain Dew做的
樱桃味饮料?
Look, I was going over the schematics
on my zero-G toilet,
听着 我在看我零重力厕所的图纸
and I made a teeny tiny mistake
发现在分流阀的设计上
on the specifications
for the diverter valve.
犯了一个小小的错误
How teeny tiny?
有多小?
It's gonna fail
after about ten flushes.
冲10次水差不多就挂了
- But the mission is for six months.
- See, that's the code red.
- 但这任务是要持续6个月的
- 对啊 这就是紧急情况
It's kind of like a jack-in-the-box.
这有点像小丑盒子
No one knows exactly when,
but at some point
没有人知道具体时间 但不定时的
something way worse than a puppet
is gonna pop out of that box.
会有比玩偶更糟糕的东西
从那盒子里喷出来
Have you notified NASA?
你给NASA报告了吗?
Are you crazy?
What am I gonna say?
你疯了吗? 我要怎么说?
"I screwed up your toilet
and there's gonna be crap floating
"我把你们的厕所搞砸了
以后会有大便漂浮在
"all over your nice
shiny space station"?
你们那整洁明亮的空间站里?"
What are you gonna do?
你要怎么办?
I'm gonna figure out how to fix it,
then I'll tell them.
我要弄清楚怎么修
然后再告诉他们
So, what do you need us for?
那你需要我们做什么呢?
He can't figure out how to fix it.
他弄不清楚怎么修
You said you were
gonna be supportive.
你说你会支持我的
I'm trying, but you have to admit
this is pretty damn funny.
我是啊
但你得承认这太他妈好笑了
I agree.
我同意
It's the juxtaposition of the high-tech
nature of space exploration
这关系到太空爆炸的高科技特性
against the banality
of a malfunctioning toilet
和厕所故障的平凡特性的对立
that provides the comic fodder here.
这是个喜剧素材哦
Check your messages.
快读你的信息
All right,
this is an exact duplicate
好的 这就是了
of the Wolowitz Zero-Gravity
Human Waste Disposal System
Wolowitz零重力人类废物处理系统
的复制品
as deployed on the
International Space Station.
为国际空间站设计
Don't you mean the Wolowitz Zero-Gravity
Human Waste Distribution System?
你的意思不是Wolowitz
零重力人类废物排放系统吧?
Good one.
这不错
It's hilarious. Now...
太好笑了 现在...
Here's an approximation
这里有空间站里
of the spare parts
available on the Space Station.
有可能找到的所有零件
We gotta find a way,
using nothing but this,
我们要想出一个方法 只用这些
to reinforce this so the waste material
avoids the spinning turbine.
来改造这个 那样废物就能避开
旋转的涡轮机了
You mean so it doesn't hit the fan?
你是说那样就碰不到风扇了?
I have to say,
我得说
I thought the toilet humor would
get less funny with repetition.
我想这厕所幽默再说下去
就不这么好笑了
Apparently, there is no law
很显然 没有法律规定
要减少带太空大便返回嘛
of diminishing comedic returns
with space poop.
- 嘿 Leonard
- 嘿 Stuart
You busy?
你有空吗?
Classified, Leonard.
要保密哦 Leonard
Yeah, it's a regular
Manhattan Project.
嗯 这可是个曼哈顿工程啊
(二战期间美国原子弹秘密工程)
What's up?
什么事?
Tonight's my date with Penny
今晚我要和Penny约会
and since we haven't been able
to connect by phone...
因为我们没能用电话联系上
I'm sorry, it's been broken.
抱歉 电话坏了
- Or e-mail.
- Yeah, that too. Everything's broken.
- 电邮也不行
- 对 那也是 所有东西都坏了
Anyway, I was just wondering
if you had any last-minute advice.
总之 我只是想知道你有没有
什么最后的建议
All right, well,
off the top of my head,
好的 眼下我能想到的就是
I think the most important thing
with Penny is to go really slow.
和Penny在一起最重要的事
就是要慢一点
I mean, glacial.
我是说 冷淡
Guys come onto her all the time,
so, you need to set yourself apart.
追她的男人多的是 所以
你得把自己和他们区别开
Be a little shy,
害羞一点
don't make too much eye contact.
不要做太多眼神接触
And, you know, treat her
with, like, cool detachment
把她当作外人一样对待
and-and, you know, fear.
还有... 害怕
- Fear?
- Yeah, like,
- 害怕?
- 对 就像
you're afraid
that if you touch her, she'll break.
你会怕如果你碰她一下 她会碎那样
Well, that plays
right into my wheelhouse.
哦 这我还蛮擅长的
Good, good.
You kids have fun tonight.
好 好的 你俩今晚玩好啊
Thanks, Leonard.
谢了 Leonard
What is that thing anyway?
那东西到底是啥?
You don't know what this is?
你不知道这是什么?
Good. Get out.
好的 滚出去
Be afraid of Penny.
要害怕Penny
Nice. Very crafty.
不错哦 相当狡猾
It wasn't bad advice.
It's just wasn't particularly helpful.
这建议也不是搅局
只是没有那么有用而已
For what it's worth, my mother says
不管怎样 我妈妈说过
that when we deceive
for personal gain,
当我们为了个人利益去骗人时
we make Jesus cry.
我们会把耶稣弄哭的
All right, what if we use
this two-inch PVC
好的 如果我们用
这两英尺的聚氯乙烯
- to reinforce the center cross-support?
- No good.
- 来改造中心支撑结构怎样?
- 不行
It might work for the Japanese
and the Americans,
那可能会对日本人和美国人有用
but have you seen the size
of the Russians they got up there?
但你见过他们弄上去的
俄罗斯人的块头吗?
This thing has to hold up
against a hearty potato-based diet.
这东西得能撑住
一餐丰盛的土豆大餐
I feel terrible.
我感觉很糟糕
Maybe if you were helping,
you'd feel better about yourself.
如果你能帮忙的话
可能你会感觉好一点
I deliberately tried
to sabotage Stuart's date with Penny.
我故意破坏Stuart和Penny的约会
Of course you feel terrible.
You completely screwed up your karma.
你当然会感觉很糟糕啦
因果轮回要糟报应了
You don't really believe
in that superstition, do you?
你不会真的相信那鬼话吧?
It's not superstition.
It's practically Newtonian.
这不是迷信 这其实是在信仰牛顿
(牛顿也是神学专家)
For every action,
there's an equal and opposite reaction.
对于每个动作
都有一个平等的对立的反应
Leonard pretends to be a friend
and acts like a two-faced bitch.
Leonard假装是朋友
而实际上则是个两面的贱人
Therefore, he is reborn
as a banana slug.
所以 他会转世投胎成
一个香蕉蛞蝓
It's actually a very elegant system.
You know, what goes around comes around.
这其实是个很好的系统
对吧 一报还一报
Speaking of what goes around
comes around...
说到一报还一报...
Okay, look.
好的 听着
Instead of trying to reinforce
this structure here,
与其试着改造这东西的结构
what if we just ran another line,
bypass it entirely?
还不如我们扯出一条线
来完全回避它
It won't work. The diameter
of the tubing is insufficient.
这没用的 管道的直径不够
What if we reposition
the collection tank?
那换换集污舱的位置怎么样?
It won't work. No way to mount it.
没用的 没法安装
Okay, here's an idea.
What if I change my name and go live
好吧 我有个主意
我们改名换姓 然后去
with my cousin and her husband, Avi,
in Israel?
以色列和我的表亲
和她丈夫Avi一起住怎么样?
That could work.
倒是一招
- Morning.
- Morning. What's up?
- 早上好
- 早上好 什么事?
Nothing. We just pulled an all-nighter
trying to fix a zero-gravity...
没 我们只是在熬夜修一个
零重力...
pasta maker.
意粉机
I'm gonna make a coffee run.
Do you want any?
我正要去煮咖啡 你要吗?
No, thanks. I have coffee.
谢啦 我自己有
Great. So how'd it go
with Stuart last night?
好的 昨晚跟Stuart怎么样?
I really don't want
to talk about it.
不堪回首啊
Yeah. Right. Sure.
是啊 没错 当然
The thing is,
before you guys went out,
但是呢 你们出门之前
I spoke to him and...
我俩有过谈话...
I said I don't want
to talk about it.
我说了 我不想回首
I just... I kind of...
我只是...有点...
What goes on between me and Stuart
is none of your business.
我俩的事与你无关
So just leave it alone, okay?
别八卦了 行吗?
If you want to clean up your karma,
go get my freakin' latte.
要想下辈子投好胎 就给我煮杯拿铁去
Hang on, I think I've got this.
Help me see if we can wedge
等下 我找到了这个 看看能否...
this little piece of PVC
behind the support rod.
把这块PVC楔进载体棒后面
You're overestimating
the tensile strength
你高估了你做的基础部分的抗张强度
of the substructure you're building.
Sheldon 我知道自己在干什么
Sheldon, I know what I'm doing.
如果你知道 那这放咖啡桌的地方
If you knew what you were doing,
there wouldn't be a space toilet
就不该摆着你的太空厕所
where my coffee table should be.
Howard 等等
Howard, wait.
为什么不用这个代替PVC
Why don't you use this
instead of the PVC
来保持横向滤波器装配到位呢?
to keep the transverse
filter assembly in place?
这又不是太空站的部件
Because this is not a spare part
from the space station.
这是比萨饼盒子里的
This is the thing from the pizza box
为了不让奶酪粘在盒子上
that keeps the lid
from touching the cheese.
干这个用的? 在印度 奶酪就会粘盒子啊
That what that's for?
In India, the lid touches the cheese.
当然了 印度那么穷 还经常爆发霍乱
Of course, we also have rampant poverty
and periodic outbreaks of cholera,
所以盒子粘上奶酪也不算啥
so a little cardboard in our cheese
is no biggie.
- 你要去哪?
- 漫画店
- Where are you going?
- Comic book store.
好主意 我也要休息下
An excellent idea!
I could certainly use a break.
- 我也是
- 等宇航员能安全排便了
- Me, too.
- You can go to the comic book store
你们才能去漫画店
when man can once again
safely poop in space.
为什么Leonard能去?
Why does Leonard get to go?
因为Penny的事 搞得他心烦意乱
'Cause he's upset
over his situation with Penny
如果他再讲一遍 我就扁死他
and if I have to hear about it again,
I'm going to kick him in his ovaries.
- 感谢理解 Howard
- 我支持你 好姐妹
- Thanks for understanding, Howard.
- I got your back, sister.
好了 要模拟实验一下了
All right, I think we've got
a prototype ready to test.
把那塑料盒给我
Hand me that Tupperware.
好沉啊
That's heavy.
当然沉了 这是我妈做的肉馅糕
Damn right it's heavy.
It's my mother's meat loaf.
一直是我测试厕所的道具
It's been testing toilets
for generations.
容我说一句
I must say,
如果跟麻省理工汇报下你现在的详细情况
I think a detailed letter to MIT
describing your current circumstances
你的硕士学位就飞鸟
might entitle you
to a refund on your master's degree.
好了 模拟零重力人类废物处理实验
Okay, simulated zero-gravity
human waste disposal test
放入肉馅糕模拟物...
with meat loaf analog in...
三 二 一
three, two, one.
好赞
Fascinating.
你觉得问题在哪?
What do you think the problem is?
面包渣太少了
Not enough bread crumbs.
Stuart 咱俩要谈谈
Hey, Stuart, I need to talk to you.
- 好啊 怎么了?
- Penny的事 我帮倒忙了
- Sure, what's up?
- I gave you bad advice about Penny,
- 我想道歉
- 没 你的建议挺好啊
- and I want to apologize.
- No, your advice was great.
- 啊?
- 是啊 慢慢来很管用
- It was?
- Yeah, going slow really worked.
开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
在我身上就不管用
Never worked for me.
昨晚吃饭时 我按你说的做了
Last night at dinner,
I did what you told me.
放慢速度 保持距离
I went really slow,
I kept my distance,
两杯酒下肚 我俩就去车里嘿咻了
and two bottles of wine later,
we were making out in my car.
酒? 我没说给她喝酒啊
Wine? I didn't say to give her wine.
这不是重点 糟糕的事才开始
It doesn't matter,
that's where it all went to hell.
接吻时很糟糕?
During the kissing?
在她嘴里打喷嚏了?
我对别的姑娘那样过
What did you do, sneeze in her mouth?
I did that to a girl once.
没 都挺好 挺火辣的
No, everything was good
and really hot.
然后我说
And I said,
"哦 Penny"
"Oh, Penny,"
而她本该说"哦 Stuart" 但她说了...
and right where she was supposed to say,
"Oh, Stuart," she said...
你的名字
your name.
Leonard?
That is your name, right?
这是你的名字吧?
I'm sorry. That must've been
the last thing you wanted to hear.
不好意思啊 你最不想听见这个了吧
It beats,
"You know I'm a dude, right?"
还不如"你知道我是爷们儿吧?"
Yeah, it was pretty bad.
是啊 糟糕死了
No doubt, no doubt.
必然的 必然的
I'm sorry it didn't work out.
不好意思 结果这么糟
Not your fault.
不是你的错
Yeah, how about that?
可不是嘛
- See you soon.
- Sure.
- 回头见
- 嗯了
Yes, sir, I understand "classified."
是的 我明白这是机密
We'll keep it all classified;
no one has to know but you and me.
天知地知 你知我知
What's classified?
啥机密?
Howard's space toilet.
I'll tell you later.
Howard的太空厕所 回头慢慢跟你说
Well, they've deployed our solution.
他们应用了我们的补救方案
Let's just all hope it works.
希望起作用
I don't see why I have to worry.
不知道我为啥要担心
My career's not hanging
in the balance.
又不是我的事业悬而未决
That was a joke.
开玩笑呢
It's funny,
很好笑
because it's true.
因为这是事实
Leonard, could you pass
the soy sauce, please?
Leonard 把酱油给我好吗?
I'm sorry, were you talking to me?
你是跟我说话呢吗?
Yeah, I said "Leonard."
是啊 我叫的是"Leonard"
Yes, you did, didn't you?
没错嘛 是不是?
What the hell is that?
那是什么鬼东西?
Meatloaf.
肉馅糕
What was it doing on the ceiling?
怎么跑天花板上去了?
That's classified.
这是机密
Houston,
International Space Station.
国际空间站
休斯顿 这里是国际空间站
We have a little situation up here.
我们这有点小状况
We'd like to make
an unscheduled space walk.
我们要临时安排一次太空行走
I.S.S., Houston.
国际空间站 这里是休斯顿
Which crew members would be
involved in this E.V.A.?
将有哪些成员出舱?
Houston, we'd all like
to step outside for a few minutes.
我们都想出舱走走
I.S.S., I'm afraid
we can't authorize that.
这将不予批准
Houston,
this is more of an FYI call.
其实我们只是通知一下
We are basically out the door.
我们已经被迫出舱了